Lucian Davidescu



lucian.davidescu94@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/lucian-davidescu-212ab011b



https://luciandavidescu.com

Summary

As a senior Java full stack developer with 7+ years of experience, I bring a wealth of expertise and passion to the table when it comes to designing and implementing software solutions for clients. My skillset includes a wide range of technologies, including:

Backend:

 Java / Spring / Spring Boot / JPA / Hibernate / PostgresSQL / MSSQL / REST / Firebase /Firestore / NoSql / Mockito / JUnit / Camunda / Nuxeo

Frontend:

React / TypeScript / Javascript / ¡Query / HTML / CSS / Struts2 / Wicket / Flutter / Polymer

DevOps:

Docker / Jenkins / SVN / Git / Maven / Sonar / Linux

Other:

Agile Scrum / Jira / Youtrack / Team leader / Project manager

I am highly experienced in utilizing these technologies to deliver effective and efficient software solutions, and I am available for contract or freelance work. My goal is to use my knowledge and skills to help clients achieve their business objectives by providing them with robust and reliable software.

Experience



Senior Software Engineer

Maretha Solutions

Sep 2022 - Present (5 months)

I work for Maretha and I am currently learning Nuxeo technology. I have been able to quickly learn the basics and have already had the chance to apply what I have learned on various projects. https://maretha.io/



Senior React Developer • Project Consultant

Remote Work

Feb 2022 - Sep 2022 (8 months)

eQualifai

As a developer at eQualifai, I was part of a team that was committed to improving education through technology. I used my skills in React to build the frontend of our tutoring platform, ensuring that it was visually engaging and user-friendly for our students. I was passionate about my role in the company and constantly sought out new ways to enhance the platform and provide an even better experience for our users. My contributions at eQualifai made a real impact in the field of education and helped students achieve their full potential.

https://equalifai.com/

Skills: React / Typescript / Redux Toolkit / MUI / Vite / Docker / Google Cloud



Senior Java Full Stack Engineer • Project Consultant

Remote Work

Feb 2022 - Sep 2022 (8 months)

Codemart

As a highly skilled and experienced contractor, I am proud to continue my work with Codemart, my previous employer. My primary goal is to help the team improve their development and delivery velocity by providing technical assistance, backlog refinements, and feature discovery for their complaint management system. This system is used by multiple regions of Germany's public transportation industry to handle customer complaints efficiently.

Skills: I continue to use the skills I previously learn



🏊 Senior Java Full Stack Engineer • Consultant • Contractor • Freelancer

Remote Work

Feb 2022 - Present (1 year)

I work as a Senior Java Full Stack Engineer / consultant / contractor / freelancer and help businesses develop their software solutions.

My programming language of choice is Java, but I am also very found of implementing solutions using Javascript / React and some other few I've described above.



🙀 Team Leader • Project Manager

Codemart

Feb 2020 - Feb 2022 (2 years 1 month)

- # Successfully leading a 8-person team into designing and implementing all requirements
- # Improved code quality by continuous refactoring on both backend and frontend side
- # Improved team development and delivery velocity by providing technical assistance, backlog refinements and feature discovery
- # I've learn how to better optimize my work and to come with fast answers for any question and started to be more people-oriented than task oriented as I was as a simple developer.
- # Responsible for training junior team members

Skills: Agile scrum + JIRA/Youtrack for managing tasks



🙀 Software Engineer

Codemart

Aug 2016 - Feb 2020 (3 years 7 months)

- # Optimized automation tests by using docker and Jenkins pipelines. Drastically reduced deploy time on demo servers by using Jenkins pipeline. This also enhanced team productivity by having to maintain only one type of deployment configuration.
- # Improved data loading performance from 10s to under 1s by redesigning the transport model removing unnecessary data fetch calls and fine-tuning the data layer, creating special DB indexes.

Refactored and optimized legacy code and migrated a Struts-XML Spring based architecture to the client-server architecture using spring boot with rest calls and REACT framework for frontend # Integrated flyway usage into a multi-module project

I've manage to get experience with some frameworks and the opportunity to see every part of developing an application:

Skills: Struts2, Wicket, React + Typescript, Javascript, jQuery, HTML/CSS

- · Java 11, Maven, Spring framework, Spring Boot, Hibernate/JPA
- PostgresSQL, SQLServer
- · Jenkins, Docker, Linux
- · GIT, Subversion SVN



🙀 Software Engineer Internship

Codemart

Jul 2016 - Aug 2016 (2 months)

Had the chance to apply what I've learnt in university and to learn new skills

Co-Founder

Clover Tech Romania

Nov 2019 - Feb 2022 (2 years 4 months)

CharityDiscount (www.charitydiscount.ro) is one of the product developed by Clover Tech Romania. It's a cashback platform and if you make your online shopings using our platform you will receive back an amount of money but it's only in Romania for now.

I had the oportunity to work with some modern technologies for this platform and to work for my own business:

- React, Typescript Redux for Web
- Flutter for Mobile

BasS:

Google Cloud + Firebase + Functions + Firestore (NoSQL DB)

Revision control:

- GIT



Information Technology Specialist

SC CHIMDET SRL

Aug 2013 - Jul 2016 (3 years)

The client is a local business whose main activity is to produce and deliver different kinds of liquid detergents.

Eliminated more than 50 hours of monthly manual work by designing and implementing a Java solution to automatise the work.

Skills: Java, JavaFX, HTML/CSS, Maven, Spring, Hibernate, MySQL

Education



Technical University of Cluj Napoca

Economics master degree, Computer Science in Economy 2017 - 2019

Technical University of Cluj Napoca

Engineer's degree, Computer Science 2013 - 2017

Licenses & Certifications

Scrum Master Certified (SMC) - Scrum Alliance Issued Jun 2018 - Expires Jun 2020

Cambrige ESOL - University of Cambridge

ECDL - ECDL ROMANIA